Mia Williams

Junior Front-End Developer | React Expert

@ help@enhancv.com @ linkedin.com • Washington, D.C.

SUMMARY

Energetic Junior Front-End Developer with over 2 years of professional experience focusing on React-based applications. Proficient with JavaScript, TypeScript, and Git. Developed over 10 user-centered React applications and troubleshooted 50+ website properties. Looking forward to adding value through my passion and expertise.

EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer

Syntax Technologies

2019 - 2020

Washington, D.C.

Contributed to frontend development with a primary focus on React-based applications.

- · Developed 10+ user-focused, modern React applications resulting in 15% improved user experience.
- Troubleshot and maintained 7 company websites, ensuring fast and optimal performance.
- Worked closely with the content team to optimize websites for accessibility and speed, increasing site traffic by 20%.

Web Developer

Innova Solutions

2018 - 2019

Washington, D.C.

Responsible for designing and maintaining company's web properties.

- · Implemented React Hooks in 5 projects, enhancing code reusability and
- Utilized Git for version control across all projects, ensuring seamless team collaboration.
- Identified and fixed 50+ issues in web properties, improving website usability.

Web Development Intern

Neural Networks

2016 - 2018

Washington, D.C.

Part of the development team working on frontend technologies.

- Gained hands-on experience with JavaScript and TypeScript, contributing to various development projects.
- Assisted in maintaining and troubleshooting portfolio of websites ensuring seamless user experience.
- Developed understanding of Sass and Bootstrap, working on side projects and tasks.

EDUCATION

Master's degree in Computer Science

Georgetown University

2015 - 2017

Washington, D.C.

Bachelor's degree in Information Technology

American University

STRENGTHS



Adaptability

Quickly adapted to the sophisticated React ecosystem at Syntax Technologies, contributing to major projects within the first few months.



Collaborative

Successfully collaborated with a team of developers and content creators at Innova Solutions, improving site traffic by 20%.



Dedicated Learner

Consistently kept up-to-date with the latest technologies, including a proficient understanding of Mobx and MST while at Neural Networks.

SKILLS

React	React Hooks	JavaScript	
TypeScrip	t Mobx	MST	Sass
Bootstrap	Git		

CERTIFICATION

Advanced React and Redux

Certificate Course by Udemy focusing on advanced concepts of React and Redux.

Modern JavaScript: From Novice to Ninja

Completed comprehensive course by Udemy on Modern JavaScript.

PASSIONS



Web Development

I love creating interactive, efficient, and user-friendly web applications that add value to businesses.



Learning Coding Languages

Spending time deep-diving into new coding languages and web technologies stimulates and inspires me.

> Powered by CY Enhancy

English

Native ••••